Guide to the Faculty records,1896-2000.
Cornell University College of Arts and Sciences Faculty Records, 1896-2000.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Faculty records, 1896-2000.
14-1-1269
Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences.
10.2 cubic ft.
Minutes of various committees.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Consists of minutes of various Committees and Boards pertaining to academic life.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Consists of faculty minutes, and minutes and other records of the Administrative Board in Charge of Freshmen and Sophomores, Advisory Board for Underclassmen, Committee on Academic Records, Committee on Admission, Committee on Common Studies, Committee on Conduct of Examinations, Educational Policy Committee, Honors Committee, the Standing Curriculum Committee, the Special Committee on Curriculum of the College of Arts and Sciences, and the General Education Committee.
Records, 1959-1964, of the Special Committee on Curriculum of the College of Arts and Sciences include memoranda between the Committee and departments of the College regarding their curricula and requirements; curriculum proposals; changes in admission procedures and programs of study; report of the Committee and comments on the report; studies of accepted candidates for admission by the Office of Admissions; reports of subcommittees; minutes of meetings; and other records; much of the correspondence is addressed to or from Committee Chairman Robert B. McLeod or Secretary G. Ferris Cronkhite.
Records of the General Education Committee, chaired by Professor Theodore Lowi, date from 1975 to 1978.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cronkhite, G. Ferris.; Lowi, Theodore J.; McLeod, Robert B.; Cornell University--Admission.; Cornell University--Curricula.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences--Faculty.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Administrative Board in Charge of Freshmen and Sophomores.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Advisory Board for Underclassmen.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Committee on Academic Records.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Committee on Admission.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Committee on Common Studies.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Committee on Conduct of Examinations.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Educational Policy Committee.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Honors Committee.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Standing Curriculum Committee.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. Special Committee on Curriculum of the College of Arts and Sciences.; Cornell University. College of Arts and Sciences. General Education Committee.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 9 is restricted to permission of office of origin.
CONTAINER LIST
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences" (Bound Volume), 1896-1906 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences" (Bound Volume), 1906-1913 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences" (Bound Volume), 1913-1920 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences" (Bound Volume), 1920-1930 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences" (Bound Volume), 1930-1940 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences" (Bound Volume), 1940-1950 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences" (Bound Volume), 1949-1955 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences" (Bound Volume), 1956-1962 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes." Minutes of the College of Arts and Sciences. Spring Binder, 1963-1968 (Box 1)
- "Faculty Minutes, Arts and Sciences", 1968-1971 (Box 1)
- "Administrative Board in Charge of Freshmen and Sophomores" (F.F.), 1908-1909 (Box 2)
- "Administrative Board in Charge of Freshmen and Sophomores" (F.F.), 1910-1914; 1917-1918 (Box 2)
- "Advisory Board for Underclassmen." Minutes of the Advisory Board. Looseleaf Notebook, 1919-1920 (Box 2)
- "Advisory Board for Underclassmen." Minutes of the Advisory Board. F.F., 1922-1924 (Box 2)
- "Advisory Board for Underclassmen." Minutes of the Advisory Board. Letter Box, 1923-1940 (Box 2)
- "Advisory Board for Underclassmen." Minutes of the Advisory Board. Spring Binder, 1940-1958 (Box 2)
- "Arts and Sciences, Committee on Academic Records." Minutes of the Committee. V.B. (damaged), 1906-1912 (Box 2)
- "Arts and Sciences, Committee on Academic Records." Minutes of the Committee. loose leaf Volume, 1915-1918 (Box 2)
- "A.R.C." Minutes of the Committee. loose leaf Volume, 1919-1920 (Box 2)
- "A.R.C." Minutes of the Committee. loose leaf Volume, 1921-1924 (Box 3)
- "Committee of Academic Records." Minutes of the Committee. F.F., 1924-1925 (Box 3)
- "A.R.C." Minutes of the Committee. Letter Box, September 1924-September 1937 (Box 3)
- "Academic Records - carbons." Minutes of the Committee. F.F., 1924-1925 (Box 3)
- "Academic Records" Minutes of the Committee, January 1938-July 1942 (Box 3)
- "Academic Records" Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, August 1942-November 1946 (Box 3)
- "Academic Records" Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, January 1947-July 1949 (Box 3)
- "Academic Records" Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, July 1949-July 1953 (Box 3)
- "Academic Records" Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, September 1953-September 1958 (Box 3)
- "Committee on Adm." Minutes and supporting papers of the Committee. Spring Binder, 1925-1926 (Box 3)
- "Common Studies, Committee on" F.F., 1957-1958 (Box 3)
- "Committee on Conduct of Examinations Exhibits." Minutes, correspondence, notes and exhibits of the Committee. F.F., 1925-1941 (Box 3)
- "Committee on Conduct of Examinations." Minutes of the Committee. F.F., 1927-1947 (Box 3)
- "Committee on Conduct of Examinations." Letters, examination books, reports and term papers re the Committee's business. F.F., 1940-1941 (Box 3)
- "Committee on Conduct of Examinations." Minutes, correspondence notes and exhibits re the Committee's buisness. F.F., 1943-1945 (Box 3)
- "Committee on Conduct of Examinations." Minutes of the Committee. F.F., 1945 (Box 3)
- "Committee on the Conduct of Exams - Duplicate Minutes." F.F., 1945-1948 (Box 3)
- "Committee on the Conduct of Exams - Cases." Correspondence and reports re the buisness of the Committee. F.F., 1948-1949 (Box 3)
- "Conduct of Examination Letters to Students outside Arts and Sciences, July 1, 1940 ." Minutes and letters re Committee buisness. F.F., 1940-1945 (Box 3)
- "Educational Policy Committee - Minutes." Spring Binder, 1904-1923 (Box 4)
- "Educational Policy Minutes." Spring Binder, October 1923-May 1934 (Box 4)
- "Educational Policy Minutes." Spring Binder, September 1934-March 1941 (Box 4)
- "Educational Policy Committee, Minutes." Spring Binder, April 1941-December 1945 (Box 4)
- "Honor Committee Record." Forms, letters and notes re the Committee work. Post bound book, 1923-1927 (Box 4)
- "Honor Committee - College of Arts and Sciences." Minutes and reports re the Committee work. Binder, 1927-1948; 1951 (Box 4)
- "Comm. on Conduct of Examinations", 1937-1948; 1951 (Box 4)
- "Standing Curriculum Committee." Minutes of the Committee, Mar. 1961-May 1964 (Box 4)
- "Educational Policy Committee." Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, January 1946-June 1950 (Box 5)
- "Educational Policy Committee." Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, September 1950-April 1956 (Box 5)
- "Educational Policy Committee." Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, May 1956-June 1961 (Box 5)
- "Educational Policy Committee." Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, October 1961-June 1966 (Box 5)
- "Educational Policy Committee." Minutes of the Committee. Spring Binder, 1966-1969 (Box 5)
- 4 volumes of Educational Policy Commmittee notebooks, 1969-1974 (Box 5)
- Special Committee on Curriculum of the College, 1959-1961 (Box 6)
- General Education Committee Records, 1975-1978 (Box 7)
- 1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- 1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- 1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- 1971 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- 1974 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
- 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
- 1977 (Box 8, Folder 12-16)
- 1978 (Box 8, Folder 17-20)
- 1979 (Box 8, Folder 21-23)
- Committee Minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1-9)
- Committee Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 10-16)
- Committee Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 17-25)
- Committee Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 26-34)
- Committee Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 35-43)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1986 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1986 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1987 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1987 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1987 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1988 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1988 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1988 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1989 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1989 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1990 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1990 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1991 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1991 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1991 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1992 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1992 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1993 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1993 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1993 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1994 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1994 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1994 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1994 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1995 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1995 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1996 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1996 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1996 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1996 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1996 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1997 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1997 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1997 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1997 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1998 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1998 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1998 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1998 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 1999 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1999 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Educational Policy Committee, Fall 1999 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 2000 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Educational Policy Committee, Spring 2000 (Box 12, Folder 7)